Robert Underwood

Experience in Oil and Gas as Automation Tech, 3D Mechanical CAD and CNC Programming.

Midland, TX 79705 Email: robert@rduexp.com Mobile/Text: (432)413-0943

Work Experience Portfolio: https://rduexp.com

Summary

Experienced in Oil and Gas Automation, Mechanical Cad Design and CNC Programming. I have a good understanding of pneumatics, hydraulics, valves, actuators, drive motors, and pumps. Good understanding of electrical power circuits, logic controllers, PLC ladder logic, and HMI. Proven track record of success in CNC manufacturing and mechanical CAD design.

Work Experience:

2023-Present: Silverline Services, Oil and Gas

- Prep and terminate well head control enclosures.
- Set, install new Well Head boxes, Commission for new ESP wells.
- Install and terminate automation components for new and existing CTB facilities.
- ESP to Rod Pump conversions.

2006-2023: MCO Construction, ID Pipe Coating Equipment, Odessa, Texas

- Design parts and prototypes using CAD software Autodesk Mechanical and Inventor
- Program CNC Lathe, Mill, Plasma/Oxy-Fuel burn table
- Create rendered 3D Mechanical illustrations for Marketing, Engineering

1991-2006: The Bosworth Company, Midland, Texas

- 13 years (HVAC) Commercial service and installs of heating and cooling pipe systems
- Medical gas piping installs at Medical Center Hospital and ORH, Odessa, Texas
- Autocad for CNC burn table, sheet metal profiles, Piping systems

Education:

1999-2000: Midland College, Midland, Texas

- Computer graphics I and II CAD software, 2 semesters
- Controls and power circuits, HVAC design

Skills:

- Automation Tech. Oil and gas related.
- CAD software: Autodesk Mechanical and Inventor .
- CNC Lathe, Mill, Plasma/Oxy-Fuel burn table programming .
- 3D Solid modeling and mechanical technical illustrations.
- Experienced with Electrical power circuits and logic controllers.
- Able to read and understand Electrical Schematics.

Certificates and Certifications:

2023 CPR Certified Basic Plus 2023 SafeLand USA, Safety 2023 H2S Cert.

TEXAS STATE BOARD OF PLUMBING EXAMINERS

2000 Medical Gas Piping Installation Endorsement 1996 Journeyman Plumber license